Daniel Duclos-Cavalcanti

Computer Engineer

516-912-7975 | New York, NY | U.S. Citizen | me@duclos.dev | www.duclos.dev | linkedin | github

Summary

Finding a thesis topic at the intersection of finance and computer science naturally complemented my rigorous German education in electrical engineering, leading me to the mentorship of Dr. Sivaraman at NYU. Today I am living in New York, completing a master's degree via an exciting research collaboration that envisions a future financial exchange on the cloud.

EDUCATION

New York University

New York, USA

Computer Science - Visiting Non-Degree Graduate Student

Sept 2023 - May 2024

- Co-Authored Publication: Jasper: Fair Multicast for Financial Exchanges in the Cloud
- CSCI-GA 2250 Operating Systems A

Technical University of Munich

Munich, Germany & New York, USA

Oct 2020 - Sept 2024

M.Sc. Electrical and Computer Engineering

• M.Sc. Thesis: VM Selection Heuristic for Multicast Overlay Trees in the Cloud

• Related Coursework: Embedded Design for Machine Learning, Chips Multicore Processors, Secure SoCs for IoT, High Performance Computing for Machine Intelligence, Machine Learning Methods and Tools

Technical University of Munich

Munich, Germany

B.Sc. Electrical and Computer Engineering

Oct 2016 - Sept 2020

Experience

Research Assistant

Jul 22 - Oct 22

TU MunichMunich, Germany • Evaluated and compared the performance of various Machine Learning models across GPUs, CPUs and TPUs.

- Analyzed USB traffic through PyShark between the host and externally added TPUs.
- Generated reports to establish a Design-Space Exploration framework to guide future model deployment decisions.

Embedded Engineer Intern

Aug 2021 – Jan 2022

Molabo GmbH Ottobrunn. Germanu

- Developed tooling for state simulations of their electric motor via Linux's virtual CAN interface and mock APIs.
- Added unit-tests and code coverage to safety critical features of their motor drive embedded controller.
- Streamlined build and testing workflows via Jenkins and CMake for a team of over 10 engineers.

Tutor - Embedded Systems Programming Lab

Apr 2021 – Aug 2021

TU Munich

Munich, Germany

• Supervised and aided 20+ students on their final embedded FreeRTOS laboratory projects in C.

Publications

Jasper: Fair Multicast for Financial Exchanges in the Cloud | (Paper)

Jan 2024 - Present

- Novel cloud hosted financial exchange achieving low latency multicast service for up to 1000 market participants.
- Achieves better scalability and around 50% lower latency than the multicast service provided by AWS.
- Used kernel-bypass techniques (DPDK) to achieve ultra-low latency at up to 35K multicast packet rate.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, C++, Python, Golang, Rust, Bash, Lua, VHDL, Tcl, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Tools: Terraform, Docker, Packer, AWS, GCP, Git, Unix Shell, Makefile, CMake, Linux, Jenkins, Vim

Technologies: Cloud Computing, Computer Networking, Embedded Systems, FPGA, RTOS, Machine Learning, HPC

Frameworks: ZeroMQ, DPDK, Tensorflow, TFLite, Numpy, Pandas, OpenMPI, OpenMP, Xilinx Vivado

Certificates: UCSD: Data Structures Fundamentals, UT Austin: Embedded Systems - uC I/O

PROJECTS

Open-MPI Value Iteration | C++, Multi-Threaded, HPC

Github

Asynchronous value iteration model to distribute workload on an HPC cluster.

Hamming Code Error Detection | C, VHDL, FPGA, SoC

Github

Error detection/correction algorithm for packet transmission on Microsemi's SF2 FPGA/SoC.

FreeRTOS-SpaceInvaders | C, RTOS, Multi-Threaded

Github

• Implemented the famous arcade game as a multi-threaded FreeRTOS application in C.